She knew his face. His touch. His voice. She knew
everything about him ... But the truth.
Sommersby is a drama, thriller, mystery film directed by Jon Amiel.
Set in the South just after the US Civil War, Laurel Sommersby is just managing
to work the farm without her husband, believed killed in battle.
By all accounts, Jack Sommersby was not a pleasant man, thus when
he suddenly returns, Laurel has mixed emotions.
It appears that Jack has changed a great deal, leading some people to
believe that this is not actually Jack but an imposter.
Laurel herself is unsure, but willing to take the man into
her home, and perhaps later into her heart.
Laurel Sommersby, played by Jodie Foster.
John Robert Sommersby / Horace Townsend, played by Richard Gere.
Orin Meecham, played by Bill Pullman.
Judge Barry Conrad Issacs, played by James Earl Jones.
Buck, played by Lanny Flaherty.
Reverend Powell, played by William Windom.
Sommersby is a 1993 period romantic drama film directed by Jon Amiel from a screenplay by Nicholas Meyer and Sarah
Kernochan, adapted from the historical account of the 16th-century French peasant Martin Guerre.
Based on the 1982 French film The Return of Martin Guerre, the film stars Richard Gere and Jodie
Foster, with Bill Pullman, James Earl Jones, Clarice Taylor, Frankie Faison, and R.
Lee Ermey in supporting roles.
Set in the Reconstruction era, it depicts a farmer returning home from the American Civil War, with his
wife beginning to suspect that he is an impostor while also falling in love with him.
Sommersby was released in the United States on February 5, 1993, by Warner Bros.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised the performances and chemistry of its lead actors, as well as
Danny Elfman's musical score, and was a box office success, grossing over $140 million worldwide on a budget of $30 million.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, court
case, war veteran, ku klux klan, southern usa.
The tone is intense and mind_bending and dark.